Saton theatre-sp 차果reảo it obsene
Awakampir sa..
Sun judicial hay
That some of these are bhu ar舞
Mr. Janama Math yearseth
Janama Math night of her day
Guruvani has a pankati
Maniva Mathichi
He has a good time
He has a good time to keep his humbleness
Guruvani has a good time
He has a lot of his dignity
I wanted to get a sense
I wanted to understand more about Guru Nanak
What is the word Guru actually mean?
That is my curiosity
Guru has a very specific meaning
And the meaning of Guru is someone who shows you the path towards truth
So for example, if you have a very good chemistry teacher
And he is very good at teaching chemistry
But he is lying
He is not a Guru
He is a teacher but he is not a Guru
That was where I started from
In Sikhism it is very clear that there is a sense of community
He wanted someone to explain to him the fundamental principles of how the Sikh religion evolved
What are the practices and what is the history of Sikhs?
When I was doing the Shiva, it was naturally set up for me to question my ego
There the community is helping you do it
So the community is saying the three tenets
First idea that you have to work
Meaning that you can't be a parasite on society
Second idea that when you are working
You have to observe what you are doing
And you have to observe the effect of what you are doing on other people
And third idea that whatever you do
Some benefit of your effort has to go to other people
So that immediately builds the community
And it is the community that acts as a vehicle
For challenging the idea of the self
For challenging ego
For challenging hatred
For challenging violence
To me the most foundational thing
Is that the entire concept is built on affection
And the entire concept is built on respect of the other
Not just respect of the other person from your religion
But respect of the other from every religion
So some of why I thought I should go and see the golden temple
I had been there before
And the interesting thing was that when I went there before
I had Matha takeout and I sat in the harmender's eye
But I didn't do Shiva
Now when I did Shiva it completely transformed the experience for me
Because I felt when I am quietly cleaning the katori
I am suddenly feeling that oh I am part of a group of people who is cleaning this katori
And I am doing the work that is promoting what Guru Nanak said
I am part of community a larger system
That is protecting an idea
So that was very interesting to me
Each one of the savers I made some friends I made friends with little girl in the
Shoo Shiva which frankly I really loved working with her
She is very cute
And then there was couple little kids also
And then even other people who I met
Really who were very affectionate
You know if you look at Indian society today
And you see the anger and you see the hatred that is being spread in society
Has many examples in history Guru Nanak being one of them
That actually guide us on the path that we should be working on
And it is unfortunate that with such a treasure that this land has
We don't seriously look at that treasure
We are so busy doing our thing, trying to succeed
Trying to impress other people
Trying to make money, trying to be famous
That we forget that actually the real treasure that India brings to the world
Probably more than any other land
Or these great people
We are going through a phase
Where wisdom is lacking
Wisdom is not how intelligent you are or how smart you are or clever you are
Wisdom is how effective you are at going to the truth
Guru Nanak is wise
Mahatma Gandhi is wise, Buddha is wise
They might not have been at the time wealthy or powerful or had a lot of force
I don't think Guru Nanak had much force
Almost no force
But he had huge amount of power because he was closer to the truth
So my view is that force is always alive
Power is always the truth
So for example the United States is called Super Power
It's not a Super Power, it's a Super Force
Gandhi is a Super Power
Guru Nanak is a Super Power
And force is always destructive
Because force is always used
With fear attached to it
It's always used with anger
It's always used with hatred
I'm early on in my journey
It's not that I am reached anywhere
But I find that if I'm operating in the realm of power and I have to
You see I don't have force compared to the BJP
I don't have force compared to the RSS
They have force
They have the government of India
They have institutions, they have CBI, they have E to do whatever they do
So the only thing I have
And I cannot tell you how beautiful it is
Is I have the truth
And no matter what they do they can keep going
Their force does nothing
To the truth, it just doesn't
So that's what I would like
Young Indian people to understand
I'm very happy
K. Raujan he understood this
And he did not come like any other VIP to Ratea
Or go Matha, K. Ratea or Chalaj Ratea
I was so impressed
He was asking questions
And it was not that you've talked about something
And then it is left hanging
It was concluded
The observations were there
And then coming to a crux
Regey about the Acharya, Yatheekhoya
Up then we would move forward
Said with a very very engaging conversation
I feel that bar sir, B.K. S.I.S.A.
Sir, B.P.A.P.A.
If he is talking about the truth,
He is a selfless chef
People will get influence by what he is doing
And I think they will also come forward
Said with a lot of love
It is good to talk about the truth
In Gurubani, he says, he is a man
That means he is there for those who surrender themselves
To him
And letting your ego go
Said with a lot of love
That is the message